Processed by 繁化姬 dict-72783e4b-r1054 @ 2025/07/18 00:16:43 | https://zhconvert.org
製作: 星際迷航中國字幕組 (https://www.startrekchina.org)
翻譯: 瓦肯蔬菜湯 & 北窗高臥久息塵 & Soulzt & 舟行萬里1234 & 是大e呀 & 諾北
校對: narwhrl
時軸: narwhrl
特效: narwhrl
日期: 2025-07-18
CBS影業出品
命運早已鍛就利刃...
鑄劍者只是順應其形
— 埃斯庫羅斯 (古希臘悲劇作家)
命運
人族帝國
她回來了
She's back!
她回家了
She's home!
菲莉帕回家了
Philippa came home!
兩年過去了
Two years,
一切都還和我記憶中一樣
and everything looks exactly as I remember.
我本以為自己永遠沒法回家了
I never thought I would see this place again.
這次我們有18人
There were 18 of us this time.
都是從帝國的各個角落
Culled from every corner of the Empire
被抓到地球參加比賽
and brought to Terra for the contest.
我們被告知 接下來的幾年裡
We were told that only one of us would survive
我們當中只有一個人能活下來
the years to come.
只有一個孩子
One child
能代表最純粹的地球血統
the purest expression of the Terran identity.
他們讓我們互相殘殺
They pitted us against each other.
過了一個又一個月 人數逐漸減少
And month by month, our numbers dwindled.
那 你贏了嗎
Did... did you win?
比賽結束了嗎
Is it over?
還有兩個人活著
Two of us still live.
桑和我
San and me.
我和桑
Me and San.
我們雖為兩人
We are two
但為一體
but one.
直至永恆
Forever.
競賽當中禁止出現「朋友」這個詞
The word "friend" was forbidden during the contest,
但我們在別人聽不到的時候向對方耳語說出這個詞
but we whispered it to each other when no one could hear.
桑和我將我們的技能結合起來
San and I combined our skills
一起對付監察者和其他參賽者
against the proctor and the other contestants.
但你們當中只有一個人能成為皇帝
But only one of you could be emperor.
還剩下最後一個任務
One task remains.
最先完成任務的人就可以統治帝國
The first to complete it rules the Empire,
而另一個人
and the other spends the rest of their life
將終生侍奉新皇
in servitude to the new emperor.
你要做什麼
What do you have to do?
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你做了什麼
What did you do?!
一切舊日牽絆 皆不可再續
No ties to the old life are permitted.
人族的帝皇唯忠於職責
An emperor can only be loyal to duty.
如此帝國方能強盛
Thus does the Empire remain strong.
如此帝國方能擴張
Thus does it grow.
媽媽
Mom.
菲莉帕
Philippa.
你完成了你的對手無法下手的任務
You succeeded where your competitor could not.
把他帶過來
Bring him here.
桑缺乏勇氣 沒能通過最後的試煉
San did not have the strength to pass the final test.
現在 他的村莊仍在烈火中燃燒 昭示著他的懦弱
Even now, his village burns as a testament to his cowardice.
我愛你
I love you.
你贏得了比賽
You have won the contest.
宣布你的勝利吧
Claim your victory.
桑  走上前
San, step forward.
現在你的生命只為侍奉於她的足下
You live now only to serve at her heel.
跪下 向主宰你生命的皇帝臣服
Kneel before the one who owns your life.
我們雖為兩人
We are two...
但為一體
But one.
不再是了
Not anymore.
菲莉帕·喬久萬歲
All hail Philippa Georgiou!
皇帝萬歲
All hail the emperor!
萬歲 萬歲
Hail! Hail!
正在執行加密協議
密鑰已認證
（最高優先級訊息 來自總控 發往阿爾法小隊領隊）
（聲紋已認證 簡報開始）
我是總控
This is Control
有一條發給阿爾法小隊領隊的最高優先級訊息
with a priority message for Alpha Team Leader.
你們的新目標是菲莉帕·喬久皇帝
Your subject is Emperor Philippa Georgiou,
人族帝國的前任統治者
former ruler of the Terran Empire.
人族帝國存在於一個平行宇宙中
It's in a parallel universe
在已知歷史記錄中
with the most criminal population
該帝國的臣民最為殘暴
in recorded history.
即使在那個宇宙 喬久仍能以暴政完全掌控帝國的每個角落
Even there, Georgiou had the market cornered on atrocities.
2257年 她被帶到我們的宇宙
In 2257, she was brought to our universe
並加入31區
and joined Section 31,
但幾年後 我們失去了聯絡
but after a few years, we lost contact.
聯絡丟失
（喬久目前狀態 位置已確認 化名：杜·弗朗克女士）
（恐襲威脅 一級優先級）
（卡坦條約 禁止聯邦勢力跨越邊界）
（警告 目標極端危險）
近日 我們在星聯邊境外的區域
Recently, Georgiou was spotted using an alias
發現菲莉帕·喬久以化名出現
in the border territory outside Federation space,
該地正是我們追蹤黑市新威脅的關鍵區域
where we're tracking a new threat on the black market.
接下來的任務，就交給你們了
This is where your team comes in.
聯邦簽訂的條約禁止我們跨越邊界
Federation treaty forbids us from crossing over that border,
也就意味著星際艦隊不能暗中行事
which means Starfleet cannot get its hands dirty.
你和你31區的隊伍將前往與喬久聯絡
You and your 31 team will go in, make contact with Georgiou
發現並控制那個威脅
to help identify and neutralize the threat.
但需注意
But make no mistake
惡犬咬人 多加小心
this dog bites, so watch your backs.
你們只有24小時的時間完成任務
You have 24 hours to complete the mission.
動身吧
Get to work.
通訊結束
星際迷航：31區
（星際迷航中國字幕組譯製）
星曆 1292.4
星際聯邦領空之外
（加密傳訊1）
（巴拉姆空間站上的一夜）
杜·弗朗克女士
Madame du Franc?
蜜月套房裡出了個小事故
Small incident in the honeymoon suite.
似乎是一位新娘
I'm afraid the bride molted
在快到高潮的時候蛻皮了
just as things were coming to a climax.
維吉爾 說重點
Virgil,get to the point.
我派出了一支生化小隊 並致以你的弔唁
I sent a biohazard team and your condolences.
另外 有一位顧客想和你說句話
Also, there's a customer hoping for a word with you.
他已經喝了不少 但看起來還是很清醒
He seems entirely sober but quite intoxicating.
維羅妮克·杜·弗朗克女士同意見你
Madame Veronique du Franc will see you.
阿洛克·薩哈  這位是維羅妮克·杜·弗朗克女士
Alok Sahar, Madame Veronique du Franc.
杜·弗朗克女士一般只接受預約洽談
Madame du Franc normally does business by appointment.
那我想預約一下
I'd like to make an appointment.
噢 這位紳士想預約一下
Oh, the gentleman would like to make an appointment.
就約現在
Now.
他說就約現在 女士
Now, madame.
（法語）
Impossible.
她說不可能
先退下吧 維吉爾
Au revoir, Virgil.
這玩意兒是非法的
That is illegal.
但能賺大錢
And that makes money.
我這裡是聲譽良好的生意場所
This is a reputable establishment.
據我所知可不是這樣
Not what I heard.
我們為什麼不去你的辦公室討論呢
Why don't we discuss it in your office?
我為什麼要帶你去我的辦公室呢 阿洛克·薩哈
Why would I take you to my office, Alok Sahar?
因為這玩意兒得自己試試
Because it's a hands-on experience.
我所到之處
♪ Everywhere I go ♪
人盡皆知
♪ Everybody knows... ♪
悅耳薊
Dulcet thistle.
悅耳薊已經滅絕了
Dulcet thistle's extinct.
我有很多存貨
I've got a dozen keys of this stuff.
你要來點嗎
Have you partaken?
這將是我為數不多的幾次初體驗
This would be one of my few first times.
來一杯潘趣酒
Packs a punch.
快樂的一杯
A happy punch.
乾杯
Bottoms up.
敬賺錢
To money.
敬你
To you.
好了 別說廢話了
Now, let's cut the shit.
31區來我的空間站幹什麼
What is Section 31 doing in my space station?
你覺得我會認不出來一個特工嗎
Hmm? You think I don't know an agent when I see one?
你帶領著一個六人小隊
You're heading up a team of six operatives,
分散在這個酒吧裡
and they're all over the bar.
有一個查莫人*
There's the Chameloid,
（* 電影6《星際迷航6: 未來之城》中出現的瑪緹婭就是查莫人）
這個綠血變形人
a green-blooded shape-shifter,
假裝在與一個德爾塔人*調情尋歡
trying to muster sexy time with a Deltan,
（* 在電影1《星際迷航1: 無限太空》中出現，他們的生理特質使其對大多數種族有著非凡魅力）
一個行走的情慾陷阱
a walking honey trap
31區用來轉移注意力的慣用伎倆
31's obviously using as a distraction.
可實際上查莫人是銀河系裡唯一
Except Chameloids are the only species in the galaxy
對德爾塔人的魅惑能力保持免疫的種族
immune to Deltan sexy time charm.
然後是那個穿著一身高端器械的傢伙
Then there's the guy with all the high-end mech,
傻站在後面 顯得好像他有腦子似的
standing in the back, looking like he has thoughts.
機械生命 有的可不只是蠻力
Mech life, it ain't just about the brute force.
實際上就是頭腦簡單 四肢發達
I'm gonna say heavy on artillery, low on IQ.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
還有那位瓦肯人
And we can't forget the Vulcan,
被舞台表演逗得哈哈大笑
laughing way too hard at the stage banter.
鑑於瓦肯人從來不笑
And since Vulcans never laugh,
他要麼也是個白痴
he's either an idiot, too,
（* 瓦肯人每七年經歷一次的發情時期）
要麼就是在龐發*期間腦子變得不正常了
or lost his mind during pon farr and went insane.
拜託 那明明很好笑啊
Oh, come on. That was funny.
還有你安排給他那個特別正經的人類搭檔
And the very serious human you stuck him with...
你控制一下自己
Reel it in anytime.
她看著就是一副苦大仇深的樣子
...she's got a stick so far up her backside,
一開口就能聽出來
it's coming out her mouth.
冷靜一點
Just reel it in.
那位是
That would be
加勒特上尉*
Lieutenant Garrett.
（* 瑞秋·加勒特 未來進取號-C的艦長 見《下一代》3x15）
星際艦隊的
Starfleet.
無趣到死
Where fun goes to die.
你找我花了不少時間啊
It took you long enough to find me.
只要你留在巴拉姆空間站
We knew that having you here on the Baraam
對我們來說 總有一天會派上用場
would be valuable to us one day.
好吧 我不得不說我一點兒也不感動
Well, I'm not feeling motivated to be valuable
我只為自己所用
to anyone but myself.
今夜請說願意
♪ Say yes tonight ♪
一切都可應允
♪ Say yes to everything... ♪
所以 我們就這麼開始談判嗎
So, is this where we start negotiating?
那要看情況了
Hmm, that depends.
你們是何時發現我的
How long have you known about me?
從你自前任站主那兒接手開始 我們就知道了
Ever since you took over from the previous owner,
而那位站主到現在依然下落不明
who we still haven't found.
其他的前站主也是
Well, all of.
這可不是我幹的
That wasn't me.
喬久皇帝
Emperor Georgiou,
我完全有權逮捕你
I am authorized to arrest you
抹除你的記憶
and wipe your mind clean.
但是話又說回來 我心裡還是覺得
But then again, there's a part of me
你更應當背負那些不堪回憶而活
that wants you to live with your memories.
尤其種族滅絕的那些
The genocidal ones.
你有權逮捕我
Being authorized to arrest me
不等於你有能力逮捕我
isn't the same as being able to arrest me.
你真的希望31區 希望我
You really want Section 31-- want me--
不止不休地追著你嗎
dogging you until the end of time?
無聊
Boring.
往事如影隨形啊
The past always catches up with you.
既然我們都不希望如此
And as much as both of us might hate it,
我會幫你個忙
I'm doing you a favor.
最後一次任務
One last mission.
聽著
Listen.
你相信命運嗎
Do you believe in fate?
我信
Because I do.
你無處可逃
You can't hide from it.
喬久 你在這裡什麼都不是
You're nothing here, Georgiou.
現在我給你一個機會
I'm giving you a chance to get back in.
參與這場跨越銀河的行動
In on the action on a galactic scale.
別再逃避了
Stop running from it.
成為你本該成為的人
Be who you are.
或者就在這個酒吧待一輩子
Or stay and tend bar for eternity.
那就抓緊開始吧
Let's get on with it.
菲莉帕·喬久 認識一下我的團隊
Philippa Georgiou, meet my team.
這是梅爾
This is Melle.
澤弗
Zeph.
你看起來像一把瑞士軍刀
You look like a Swiss Army knife.
等等
Uh, hold on.
我不知道那是什麼意思
I don't know what that means, but I'm not gonna
但我不可能傻站在這裡被你侮辱
just stand here and get insulted.
我沒說你
I'm not talking about you.
我是說你的裝甲
I'm talking about your suit.
鑑於你是新來的
Um, you're new,
所以我就解釋這一回
so I'm gonna just explain this one time
當你在說我這套裝甲的時候
that when you are talking about the suit,
就是在說我
you're talking about Zeph.
澤弗有點機械變形障礙症 大概
Zeph suffers from what we call mecha dysmorphia.
我也許不知道那是啥意思
And I may not know what that is,
但我也不接受你這說法
but I'm also not gonna take that from you,
小夸 我覺得你冒犯了我
Quas, and personally I'm offended.
-我覺得你應當知道  -這挺對的
- I think you should know... - Well, it's accurate.
你不能診斷我得了什麼 你不是醫生
It's not a diagnosis. You're not a doctor.
澤弗 澤弗 澤弗
Zeph. Zeph, Zeph!
-他知道 他知道 別吵了 -好吧
- He knows. He knows. He knows. - Okay, fine.
他知道
He knows.
-他明白的 他明白的 -是的
- He gets it. He gets it. - Yes.
行了 那位瓦肯人呢
Okay, what about that Vulcan?
沒人跟她說嗎
Nobody told her?
你說這個嗎 正跟你說話的這個東西
This? The thing you're talking to?
這個瓦肯外表不過是台機器
The Vulcan's just a machine.
我在裡面
I'm inside.
操控它
Driving.
我通過體內的備用駕駛艙控制這具身體
I control the body from a backup vehicle.
這是我專門用來在狹窄空間裡進出的小玩意
Yeah, something I use to get into tight spots.
你好啊
Hi there.
我是法茲
I'm Fuzz.
法茲是納米人
Fuzz is a Nanokin.
一個天性愛玩的傢伙
Real fun-loving guy.
你好
Hello.
除非他哪天不感興趣了
Except for when he's not.
然後他就會變成一個易暴易怒的人了
Then he's deranged with an anger management problem.
你該說完第一句就閉嘴的 夸西
Well, you could've stopped at the first thing, Quasi.
一個非法製造的瓦肯型運輸載體
A bootleg Vulcan conveyance?
你肯定在黑市上見過不少了不得的東西
You must see cool stuff on the black market.
納米人都是天生的拾荒者
Nanokins are pretty scavengery.
31區在廢棄的船隻上發現了蟲害
31 made first contact when we
然後才有了第一次接觸
discovered an infestation on a derelict ship.
夸西
Quasi.
啊 糟了
Oh, shit.
夸西 你再說一遍「蟲害」試試看
Say "infestation" one more time, Quasi.
叫我拾荒者 你這袋沒形狀的煙灰
Say "scavenger," you sack of amorphous soot!
我 我一順口就說出來了
I-I s-- I heard it as soon as I said it.
我真想好好揍你一頓
I will kick your ass
直到你變成一團液體的…
until you cannot form a solid mass of...
法茲 情緒控制一下
Fuzz. Fuzz. Lock it down.
我已經夠冷靜了
I am locked down.
我被困在一個巨大的瓦肯機器腦袋裡
I'm trapped inside a giant robot Vulcan head.
此刻沒人比我更「冷靜」了
No one is more locked down than me right now!
納米人情緒光譜不太穩定
Nanokins have a wonky emotional spectrum.
不不不不行
No, no, no, no, no, no,
不許用居高臨下的態度對我 梅爾
I will not be condescended to, Melle,
尤其是你 因為說實話
particularly not by you, because honest...
我愛你 你就是一切
I love you. You are everything.
你喜歡我複雜的情緒光譜嗎
Does my spectrum work for you?
我意思是 你是認真的嗎 還是說
I mean, like, like, are you into it or...
法茲
Fuzz!
她在侮辱你 老兄
She's insulting you, pal.
我就知道德爾塔人又會做他們德爾塔人的那一套
I know Deltans are gonna do their Deltan thing,
但是自尊自愛點吧 伙計
but have a little self-respect, would you?
能繼續任務了嗎
Can we continue?
然後這位是瑞秋·加勒特上尉
And that's Lieutenant Rachel Garrett.
她僅為這次任務被臨時派往31區
She is detailed to Section 31 for this one mission only.
上尉 你得罪了誰才被派來這個秘密組織?
Who did you piss off to get stuck in black ops, Lieutenant?
派個星際艦隊的人進來是確保我們行事合規
Starfleet is here to make sure we color inside the lines.
我參與本次行動的目的是保衛聯邦
Starfleet is here to defend the Federation,
維持和平狀態並確保不發生謀殺事件
keep the peace and make sure no one commits murder.
那你呢
And you?
等一下
One moment.
我認識夸西是因為
Quasi came on my radar
他證明了神經膠質細胞簇的存在
when he proved the existence of glioclusters.
神經膠質細胞簇只存在於理論中
Glioclusters are theoretical.
曾經是
Formerly theoretical.
生命充滿無限可能
Life is just branching possibilities.
它們以你能想像的任何方式盛開
You know, they bloom and blossom any way you can imagine.
比如 我現在可能會被你嚇倒
For example, I could be intimidated by you right now.
畢竟你殺了那麼多人
I mean, after all, you've murdered so many people...
而且你好像能看透我的靈魂
and you seem to be staring right into my soul.
我可以對此做出回應
I could respond to that
或者我可以觀察我的感受
or I could observe my feelings right now,
不管它 只做我需要做的事
lock it away and do what I need to do.
或者說
Or...
小夸 選一個好嗎
Quas. Pick one. Hmm?
- 好吧 - 有時夸西看到了太多可能性
- Yes. - Sometimes Quasi sees so many options
以至於他的思維可能會有所停滯
he gets brain-freeze.
多謝誇獎呢 梅爾
Thank you, Melle.
夸西 我們能繼續了嗎
Quasi, can we carry on, please?
我們的目標是達達·諾爾
Our target's name is Dada Noe.
一個有道德底線在哪都存疑的傢伙
Dubious moral compass.
在他叛變之前 他在瓦特殖民地經營著一個病理學實驗室
Ran a pathology lab on the Watt Colonies before he went rogue.
自那以後 他便開始替人訂製生化武器
Since then, he's been designing bioweapons on spec.
諾爾前往巴拉姆空間站是為了
Noe's on his way to the Baraam
把他的最新發明出手給米諾斯最高議會
to sell his latest creation to the Minosian High Council.
目前我們與米諾斯統治體之間並無正式敵對狀態
There are no formal hostilities with the Minosian Sway,
但若他們拿到這件武器
but that could change
情況可能會發生變化
if they get their hands on a superweapon.
有任何關於這個超級生物武器的信息嗎
Do we know what this bio superweapon is?
沒有 但要是諾爾成功出售就壞了
No, but if Dada Noe is selling it, it's bad.
所以你的任務目標就是確保交易不會發生
So you're here to make sure the sale never happens.
怎麼做
How?
你對我們行動的發覺確實造成了一些影響
Things went south when you spotted us,
但計劃仍然可靠
but the plan is still solid.
首先 阿洛克會
First, Alok was going to...
你說吧
You can say it.
和你親密接觸
Connect. With you.
歡迎
Welcome!
異想天開啊
What a cute idea.
一旦我們適當的分散了你的注意力
Once we had you suitably distracted,
就輪到夸西做他擅長的事了
Quasi would do the other thing Quasi does.
好了 夸西
Okay, Quasi.
麻煩你了
If you would do the honors.
沒問題
Absolutely.
我們開始吧
Let's get to work.
歡迎歡迎 達達·諾爾
Welcome, Dada Noe.
這時候法茲會參與進來
This is where Fuzz comes in.
你絕對想不到我能進入多小的地方
You wouldn't believe the tiny spots I can get into.
比如 身體改造組件的內部空間
For example, the inner workings of body modifications.
只要我進入達達的身體改造組件裡
Oh, once I fly inside Dada's body mod,
這就是我要發揮作用的時刻
well, then it's time to get to work.
這麼多電路
So many circuits.
太多可能出錯的東西了
So many things that could go wrong.
我們這位全副武裝的十字軍戰士
Competency crusader here will talk me through
會通過植入物跟我交談
the tech on the implant.
如果我認為我們通過達達·諾爾的植入物
And if I think we're putting Dada Noe's life in danger
讓他生命垂危
by tinkering with that implant,
我會通過星際艦隊
I will unleash the full weight of Starfleet
對此次任務施壓
on this whole operation.
嘿 我們討論的可是一個要出售超級武器的傢伙
Oy, we're talking about a bloke who's selling superweapons
他會把東西賣給任何有拉蒂金卡的三流恐怖分子
to any third-rate terrorist with a Latinum card.
聽仔細了 滿腦子廢品的傢伙
Listen carefully, Junkyard.
星際艦隊不執行暗殺任務
Starfleet does not do assassinations.
唉 別再滿腦子的惦記著你的最高指導原則了
Ay, don't get your prime directives in a bunch.
不會讓你親自下場弄髒手的
You are not going to get your hands dirty
也不會壞了你升艦長的前程
and mess up your chances of becoming captain.
我可是頂尖科學官
I'm a top-tier science officer.
屁股擰成麻花了
Butt pretzel.
就是個死板精
Tight-ass.
真是太不尊重人了
So disrespectful.
只要加勒特和法茲切斷了組件的鏈接
Soon as Garrett and Fuzz sever that link...
他就隨便我們拿捏了
...he'll be under our control,
我會和澤弗一起制服他
and I'll take him down with the help of Zeph.
一下搞定
That's what I call a hit.
只需一下
One.
達達·諾爾會被拘留 他的病原體會被沒收
Dada Noe and his pathogen will be in custody
這一切會在賣家出現在巴拉姆空間站之前就完成
before the buyers can even show up to the Baraam.
速戰速決
And we are in and out.
呃
Mm.
算了
Meh.
啥
Meh?
我有個更簡單的辦法
I have a simpler idea.
表情很絕望 我看的出來
♪ Desperate, I can tell ♪
所有的祈求
♪ All that begging ♪
都像是為你量身訂做的
♪ Suits you well. ♪
現在打爆我的手機
♪ Blowing up my phone now ♪
我向上 你低頭
♪ Going up, you bow down ♪
看看是誰需要誰
♪ Look at who needs who... ♪
歡迎歡迎 達達·諾爾先生
Welcome, Monsieur Dada Noe.
您的到來使巴拉姆空間站蓬蓽生輝
We're honored to have you here at the Baraam.
我是維羅妮卡·杜·弗朗克 這裡的店主
I am Veronique du Franc, the proprietor.
我早就預約我的套間了吧
I told them to have my suite ready.
當然 先生
Mais oui, monsieur.
請允許我帶您到房間裡
May I escort you to your quarters?
請隨我來
Come.
我們有最好的…
We have the most exquisite...
我簡直不敢相信你會信任這個反社會的瘋子
I can't believe you're trusting this sociopath.
上尉
Well, Lieutenant,
你做好自己的事
you got to do what you got to do,
我知道怎麼跟反社會瘋子打交道
and I'm kind of familiar with sociopaths.
我說了別帶我來
I said don't bring me.
我想您的旅程一切順利 先生
I trust your trip was without incident, monsieur.
你的團隊倒是幫我把一切都打點好了
Well, your people made everything easy.
不勝榮幸
Our pleasure.
我們到了
Here we are.
太俗氣了
So tacky.
但我想這就是你出名的地方
But I guess that's what you're known for.
這是什麼？
What's this?
這東西叫相位轉移器
It's called a phase pod.
我的某位客戶送給我的禮物
A client of mine gave it to me as a gift,
我自己也有一個
and I got one for myself, too.
你在做什麼
What are you doing?
宇宙中的一切
Everything in the universe vibrates
都以特定的波長振動
on a certain wavelength.
該死
Damn it.
把箱子還給我
Give me back my case.
我拒絕
No.
維修費從你的押金裡出
That's coming out of your security deposit.
相位轉移器則會改變
The phase pod changes the wavelength
接觸到的任何東西的物質波長
of whatever they touch.
我和你不在同一相位 你也不和我在同一相位
I am out of phase with you, and you're out of phase with me.
但是我 跟你的箱子在同一相位
I am, however, in phase with your case.
然後我會把它拿走
And I will be taking it with me.
你根本不知道你挑起了什麼
You have no idea what you've started.
哎呀
Whoopsie.
不錯嘛
Impressive.
你真的是普通人類嗎
Are you sure you're human?
多數時候是
Most days.
謝謝你
Thank you.
把箱子給我
Give me the case.
你是誰
Who are you?
他從那兒走了 那兒那兒 走那邊
He went that way. That way, that way, that way!
哇 外星人
Oh, aliens.
還是裸體的
Naked aliens.
澤弗 快追
Go, Zeph, go.
他往休息室去了 天哪 他們走得真快
He's headed to the lounge. Man, they're moving fast.
梅爾 他朝你來了
Melle, he's coming to you.
哎呀
Yikes.
沒事沒事 我還好
No, it's okay. I'm all right.
梅爾 有看到目標嗎
Melle, you got him?
看到了
Got him.
哎呀
Ooh-la-la!
嗨 親愛的
Ay, amor.
不可能
That's not possible.
它已經被我銷毀了
I had that destroyed.
不
No. No!
這不可能
It's not possible.
你知道那件武器
You knew that weapon.
是什麼
What is it?
回答我
行 那就來硬的
Fine. The hard way.
永恆的祈求者懇請覲見
The Eternal Supplicant begs approach.
（人族帝國）
（上輩子）
永恆的祈求者懇請覲見
The Eternal Supplicant begs approach.
准了
You have my permission.
參見至高無上的女皇陛下
All hail Her Most Imperial Majesty,
崇上國母
Mother of the Fatherland,
-瓦肯領主  -你帶來的是什麼
- Overlord of Vulc... - What is it?
它完成了 陛下
It is finished, Your Majesty.
我的工程師們在哪
Where are my engineers?
他們 他們在完工後結束了自己的生命
They... they took their own lives upon completion.
你在為誰流淚 桑
Who is the tear for, San?
說
Speak.
是為您 陛下
It is for you, Majesty.
這都是
It is all...
為了您
...for you.
我再問你 桑
I asked you a question, San.
你為何為我而哭
Why do you cry for me?
看著我
Look at me.
你還記得我們是誰嗎
Do you remember who we were?
在這一切之前
Before all this.
好奇的男孩
The curious boy.
天真的女孩
The innocent girl.
我只記得我的失敗 陛下
I only remember my failure, Majesty.
別對我撒謊
Don't lie to me.
為了活下去 我們付出了別人無法想像的代價
We were the only ones who could understand the cost to stay alive.
我們是一個集體
We made a team.
彼此依靠 不可分割
We needed each other, didn't we?
記得那時我們是靠著什麼話語 彼此支撐著活下來的嗎
What did we say to carry each other through, to survive together?
我們雖為兩人
We are two...
但為一體
But one.
我們雖為兩人 但為一體
We are two but one.
如果我說
If I said then,
「我們逃跑吧」
"Let's run away,
「逃離這場競爭」
"let's flee this competition
「以及把我們和人族聯繫在一起的一切」
and everything that binds us to Terra,"
你會說什麼呢
what would you have said?
您問這個問題的時機 比您認為的更富意味
The timing of your question is more poetic than you know.
我會答應您
I would have said yes.
只會在當時
Then.
那麼現在呢
But now?
您本可以在您的治下創造一些美好的東西
You could have made something beautiful with your reign.
然而 您卻選擇了讓人製造此物
Instead, you chose to build this.
這意味著我熟知的那個天真女孩
That means that innocent girl I knew,
她已經
she has been...
死了
...murdered.
怎麼回事
What is this?
你
You...
你服用了一樣的毒藥?
You took the same poison?
不 我不許你死
No! I forbid you to die!
沒有人願意活在
No one wants to live
您的統治中 皇帝
in your world, Emperor.
你就是個怪物
You are a monster!
這是什麼令人愉快的地方
And what delightful place is this?
一個安全屋
A safe house.
但對你而言也許不是
But maybe not so safe for you.
既然你是31區的
You are Section 31.
你為什麼不拷問我以獲取答案
Why aren't you torturing answers out of me?
你是個暴君
You're a tyrant.
貨真價實的
A real one.
折磨起不到半點作用
Torture wouldn't work.
你怎麼會這麼了解我這種人呢
How do you know so much about people like me?
是在哪裡學來的暴君手段 而且學得很到位
You learned tyranny somewhere, and you learned hard.
藏著掖著 只證明了你的軟弱
If you have to hide it, that's a weakness.
而我 不能容許搭檔有這種弱點
And I can't have that in a partner.
我們可算不上搭檔
We're not partners.
不是嗎
No?
我可是幫了大忙了
I've been very helpful.
你的計劃行不通
You had a plan that couldn't work.
而我給了你更好的
I gave you a better one.
你讓我嚐到了那種刺激
You gave me a taste of the action,
還明知道我會上癮
knowing I'd want more.
你需要我
You need me.
你選擇了我
You chose me.
為什麼呢
Why?
不管你認為你的任務是什麼
Whatever you believed your mission was,
這遠比你想像的更糟糕
it's worse than you thought.
事關數億萬生命 時間緊迫
Billions of lives are at stake, and time is short.
你先讓我了解你 我才能告訴你
Tell me you, and I will tell you me.
要想合作 我得知根知底
The only way this works is if I know exactly
說出你的身份
who I'm dealing with.
我也不屬於這個時代
I'm not from this time, either.
我出生於20世紀的地球
I was born on Earth, 20th century.
這麼說你已經350歲高齡了
You are 350 years old?
差不多
More or less.
大部分時間我在冬眠艙裡
I slept most of that time.
在我被流放之後
After my exile.
優生戰爭
The Eugenics Wars.
強化人
Augments...
奪走了我的星球
took my planet.
我的家鄉
My home.
當時我們差不多有十個人在戰鬥
There was maybe ten of us who fought.
我認識的人不是挨了一槍就是挨了一刀
Everyone I knew either took a bullet or a blade.
我也還以顏色
But I gave some back.
這讓她注意到了我
She noticed me.
那個屠殺我家人的強化人
The Augment who slaughtered my family.
他們叫她 被標記的吉裡
They called her Giri the Marked.
她收留了我
She took me in.
讓我比任何人類都強大
Made me stronger than any human should be.
她把我撕成碎片
She ripped me apart
然後把我重塑成了她軍隊裡的又一個強化人
and turned me into another Augment for her army.
我做了很多可怕的事
And I did terrible things.
卻是為你這樣的怪物效力
All for a monster like you.
因為對於暴君來說 永遠只有一個選擇
Because for tyrants, there is only one choice:
殺戮
murder.
但你卻沒殺掉我
You haven't killed me.
暫時而已
Yet.
我之所以能認出那個武器
I recognized the weapon because
因為它是我下令造的
I ordered it to be built.
召集你的人手
Gather your people.
每個人都得派上用場
We're gonna need every one of them.
（加密傳訊2）
（天賜之物）
在我的宇宙裡
In my universe,
陰謀重重 政敵環伺
there were always plotters.
政變層出不窮
Always a coup.
所以我造了一件武器來終結所有威脅
So I built a weapon to end all threats.
我稱之為
I called it
「天賜之物」
the Godsend.
它會引發一種連鎖反應
It triggers a chain reaction,
就像病毒一樣在群星間傳播
like a virus passing between planets.
所到之處 一切都將化為灰燼
Everything in its path incinerates.
整個象限都會消失
An entire quadrant would be lost.
如果我的敵人成功殺死了我
If my enemies managed to kill me,
那也不會有東西留給他統治
there would be nothing left to rule.
有個小問題
Yeah, hi. Quick question.
不好意思
Sorry.
就一個很小很小的問題
Yeah, no. Uh, just a qu-- it's just a quick one.
這是天賜之物還是天賜之暮
Is it Godsend or God's End?
天賜之物還是天賜之暮
Godsend or God's End?
我不明白你說的有什麼區別
I don't hear a difference in what you're saying.
聽不出來嗎 「物」和「暮」
Really? Really? Godsend. God's End.
我還是沒聽明白
Yeah, I'm still not getting it.
天賜之物是...
The Godsend is...
噢 天賜之物 我現在聽清楚了
Wait, Godsend. I hear it now.
-天賜之物 不是暮  -物
- It's Godsend. No apostrophe. - Send.
天賜之物就在這個宇宙
The Godsend is here.
怎麼會 那可是另一個宇宙的物品
How? It's from another universe.
我不知道 但那個人剛剛就拿著它
I don't know, but that man had it.
你以為是達達·諾伊的那個人
The one that you think is Dada Noe.
我們都知道是達達·諾伊的那個人
The one we know is Dada Noe.
不 他不可能是你們的達達·諾伊
No, he's not your Dada Noe. He can't be.
他來自人族帝國
He's from the Terran Empire,
是他把天賜之物帶來這裡
and he brought the Godsend here.
不然他根本不可能知道那到底是什麼
That's the only way he can know about it.
既然我們已經抓到他了
And since we have him locked up tight,
我要親自審訊他
I'll interrogate him.
絕對不行 不能信這個女人說的話
No, no, no. We cannot trust a single word this woman says.
是啊
Yeah.
她害死了梅爾
She cost us Melle.
只有她知道我們面對的是什麼人
She's the only one who knows what we're dealing with.
也就是她自己說的 小兄弟
Yeah, well, so she says, little bro.
小?
Little?
這是身材羞辱
Scale-shamer!
微生物比恐龍更長壽
Microbes outlasted dinosaurs!
冷靜點 我要說的是
Calm your boots. What I'm saying is...
我要尿在你的裝甲上 直到你全身生鏽
I will piss in your suit until you go all rusty like!
這一切都是她搞砸的
...that she's the reason this is all bollixed up.
她導致了梅爾的死
She's the reason Melle's dead,
她也是我們被派來這的原因
and she's the reason we're in the ass end of the galaxy.
聽好了
Listen up.
喬久和我回船上去
Georgiou and I are gonna go back to the ship.
達達·諾伊是我們與天賜之物的唯一聯繫
Dada Noe is our only link to the Godsend,
所以我們要找他談談
so we're gonna have a little chat with him.
幹什麼
What?
她叫菲莉帕·喬久
Her name is Philippa Georgiou,
至高無上的女皇陛下
Her Most Imperial Majesty.
崇上國母
Mother of the Fatherland.
瓦肯領主
Overlord of Vulcan.
克羅諾斯征服者 安多利女王
Dominus of Qo'noS, Regina Andor,
菲莉帕·喬久·奧古斯都·伊波尼亞斯·塞塔瑞斯
Philippa Georgiou Augustus Iaponius Centarius.
酷
Cool.
配薯條的嗎
That come with fries?
很好笑 對吧
That was good, right?
好吧
Okay.
每次你不直接回答她的問題
Every time you don't answer her questions directly,
女皇陛下就會狠狠地打你的臉
Her Majesty will punch you in your face.
好吧
Fine.
我是達達
I'm Dada.
達達·諾伊 先念達達 再是諾伊
Dada Noe. Just Dada, then Noe.
就是這樣 沒有中間
That's it. No in-betweens.
然後 我
And I, uh...
我以前在瓦特殖民地開過一家病理學實驗室
I used to run a pathology lab in the Watt Colonies.
搞什麼鬼
What the shit, man?!
你明明說揍我臉的會是她
You said that she was gonna be doing the face punching!
現在我倆都說謊了 你不是那個達達
So now we both have lied. You are not that Dada.
你是那些人口中說的他的鏡像版本
You're what these people call his Mirror.
你來自人族帝國
You came here from the Terran Empire,
而且還帶來了天賜之物
and you brought the Godsend.
什麼天賜之物
What's the Godsend?
我自己的軍事委員會曾想要廢黜我
My own war council tried to depose me.
你知道我是怎麼說服元帥開口的嗎
Do you know how I convinced the field marshal to talk?
我曾是個管理員
I was an administrator
在帝國裡的武器設施工作
at an Imperial weapons facility on Terra.
沒錯
Uh, yeah.
天賜之物被存放在我管理的設施中
The Godsend was stored at my facility.
大多數人認為這只是一個傳說
Most thought it was a legend,
但我知道這是真的
but I knew it was real.
所以你想賣掉它
So you tried to sell it.
是 是的
Yeah, yeah.
我想靠得來的收益安靜地生活在這裡
I wanted to live here quietly on its proceeds.
你是怎麼來到我們的宇宙的
How did you get to our universe?
當時發生了一場離子風暴
There was an ion storm.
實際上是兩場
Two of them, actually.
它們像對好了表一樣準時相遇
And when they converged, which they do like clockwork,
撕裂了帝國邊界某處的時空
they ripped something open on the fringes of the Empire--
他們稱之為異象
an anomaly, they called it--
但這實際上是一條通道
but it was a passageway
從人族帝國通往這裡
to get to this place from the Terran Empire.
從你們宇宙的新月星雲穿出
Comes out through your Crescent Nebula.
至少目前還是鮮有人知的
Few know about it. For now.
但它四小時後會重新開放
But it'll open again in four hours.
那本來是我要去見買家的時間
That's when I was supposed to be meeting my buyer.
你知道那武器的威力嗎
Are you aware of what that weapon does?
人族帝國已經耗盡了所有資源
The Terran Empire's burned through its resources.
饑荒肆虐 餓殍遍地
There's famine.
整個生態系統正在崩潰
Entire ecologies are collapsing.
它們需要尋找新的領土
They need to find a new territory
進行征服和壓榨
to conquer and strip-mine.
當他們意識到他們的超級武器不見了
When they realize that their superweapon is gone,
他們一定會找到那條通道
they're gonna find that passageway--
你知道他們會的 然後來到這裡
you know they will-- and they'll come
燒殺搶掠每一寸領土 再奴役餘生
and they'll burn everything they touch and enslave the rest,
您的帝國向來如此 陛下
because that's what the Empire does, Majesty.
他們學您學到了精髓
They learned well from you.
還有誰想要它？
Who else wants it?
我真的不知道
I-I don't know, man.
我收到了一個報價 錢是真的
I got an offer. The money was real.
有人偷走了我們的天賜之物
Someone stole the Godsend from us.
究竟是誰
Who was he?
我真不清楚
No idea.
無論是誰闖入我的套間 偷走了那件武器
Whoever broke into my room, whoever stole that weapon,
知道這些事的人
they know what they know
肯定是從你們其中之一得來的
because they learned it from one of you.
緊急傳送
Emergency transporter.
這下好了
Well, this is great.
更棒了
Oh, even better.
那是我們的船嗎 船炸了嗎
Is that... is that the ship? Is the ship gone?
我還挺喜歡那艘船的
I liked that ship.
什麼情況
What happened?
有人搞破壞
Sabotage.
什麼
What?
偷走天賜之物的人有一個同夥
Whoever stole the Godsend had a partner.
就在我們幾個之中
It was someone here.
這意味著我們中的一個是內鬼
Which means one of us is a mole.
可能是你
Could be you.
原話奉還
要是我的話 我早把你們都殺了
If it were me, I would have murdered all of you already.
大哥 你是了解我的
Look, boss, if there's a mole,
絕對不可能是我
you know it's not me.
雖然這話聽起來也就很像內奸說的 我也不確定
I mean, that sounds pretty moley to me. I don't know.
我們合作過差不多十次了
We've been on like ten ops together.
是沒錯 但我連你長什麼樣都不知道
Yeah, and I still don't even know what you look like, do I?
沒人知道查莫人長什麼樣子
No one knows what a Chameloid looks like.
你可以變成任何你想變的樣子
You might change into anything you want.
那法茲呢
What about Fuzz, huh?
他的體型與其他人都不在一個尺度上
He exists on a whole other scale than anybody else.
轉移話題是嗎
Mm, deflecting?
我的妻子即將產下我們的第一窩卵囊
My wife is about to lay our first litter of egg sacs.
而且我還有19萬隻幼崽正在路上
No, I have 190,000 hatchlings on the way...
- 我希望他們活下去  - 那你聽著
- and I want them to live.  - Well, look,
你可以在我們中的任何人找到動機
you could find a motive for any of us.
也可能是你們中任何兩個的組合
Or it could be a combination of any of you.
你看 就像澤弗和法茲或者其他
You know, like-like Zeph and-and Fuzz or...
你還漏掉了梅爾
You are spinning out without Melle.
你根本沒法做出判斷
You cannot land on a choice.
也許是你想給我灌輸這個觀點
Maybe you're putting that in my head
因為你才是內鬼
because you're the mole.
又會不會是加勒特 她可是新來的
Huh? How about Garrett? She's new.
她才不在乎我們
She doesn't care about us.
我可是星際艦隊的軍官
I'm Starfleet.
還有沒有人像我一樣感受到一陣英雄主義的風
Anyone else feel that heroic breeze right there
弄亂了她的斗篷?
ruffling her cape?
聽我講 那邊有一艘舊船
Okay, there's an old ship out there,
一艘舊垃圾駁船
an old garbage scow.
我發現它的時候你們還在
Yeah, I found it when you were up there
審問那個金屬腦袋
interrogating metal head.
肯定已經很多年沒人駕駛過它了
Must be years since anyone flew it,
但我認為我們可以修復它
but I think we can work with it
開著它去追捕拿走天賜之物的人
to go after whoever took the Godsend.
我沒那麼討厭你了
I dislike you less.
如果我想有人喜歡我 我就會養一隻狗
If I wanted someone to like me, I'd get a dog.
我喜歡秩序
I like order.
我喜歡預測和結論
I like prediction and conclusion.
那你可來錯隊伍了
Then you're on the wrong team
因為我們這還沒揪出內鬼
because we've got mole,
被困在一顆荒無人煙的星球
stranded on a dead planet,
無法聯絡外界
no communication with the outside,
而且不到四個小時之後人族將得到天賜之物
and less than four hours before the Terrans get the Godsend
並在銀河系的任意一處使用它
and use it anywhere in the galaxy.
說起來
Speaking of which,
小夸 天線陣列怎麼樣了
Quas, what about the antenna array?
這個嘛
Uh, well...
這玩意已經過時幾十年了
Well, it's a couple decades out of date.
我們修復它 把目前的情況告知31區
We get it up and running, then we tell 31 what's coming.
我們齊心協力
We work together.
每個人都不要離開彼此的視線
Everyone stays in sight.
好
Yeah.
我盯著呢
Just...
幹活吧
Let's go.
修好怕是沒那麼簡單了
Well, there goes that idea.
我們的小內鬼真的很忙
Our little mole has been really busy.
扯斷了所有線路
Ripped up all the wiring.
分兩個隊 我會帶一個進入樹林
Two teams. I'll lead one into the woods.
我帶三個人進樹林
I'll lead one into the woods.
試試看能不能修好那艘小艇
Three to see if we can salvage that scow.
你和其他人一起留在這裡
You stay here with the others
並嘗試修復天線陣列
and try and fix the antenna array.
怎麼輪到她來發號施令了
Why is she giving us orders now?
因為是我讓的
Because I'm letting her
而且她十有八九不是內奸
and I'm pretty certain she's not the mole.
你可不會把賭注押在「十有八九」的身上吧
You wouldn't bet on a horse named Pretty Certain.
小夸、法茲 你們馬上和喬久一起去船
Quas, Fuzz, you get to the scow right away with Georgiou.
澤弗和加勒特 你們跟我待在這
Zeph and Garrett, you stay here with me.
我們會搞定天線陣列的
We'll take care of the antenna array.
請解釋一下
Uh, I'm sorry.
我是應該出去
I'm supposed to go out into the woods
和兩個想殺我的人一起進入樹林嗎
with two people who want to kill me?
保持在彼此的視線之內 別死了就行
Just stay in sight of each other and don't get dead.
好嗎
Okay?
真是多謝了 頭兒
Yep, thanks, Cap.
我得說 50%的機率他們中的一個想殺我
I mean, just fifty-fifty shot one of them wants to kill me,
還有25%的機率
and then 25%...
別貧嘴了小夸 快出發
Quas, just get your ass out there.
我也愛你 頭兒
I love you, too, Cap.
行了行了
All righty.
遵命
Aye, aye.
這艘舊船上的內部電路
The internal circuitry on this old scow
狀態還不錯
is still in decent shape.
我看這些應該都還能用
Everything I'm seeing should work.
所以我們正在追的東西 天賜之物
So this thing we're chasing, the Godsend,
你的工程師 他們安裝保險沒有?
your engineers, did they install a fail-safe?
可以遠程解除它嗎
Can we disable it remotely?
沒有這種保險
There is no fail-safe.
我不會允許的
I wouldn't allow it.
不愧是你
How very on-brand for you.
可以再問你一個問題嗎
Can I ask you one more question?
真的最後一個問題了
I'm just gonna ask you one more question.
既然你主導了天賜之物的製造
So you brought the Godsend into the world
目的就是抹殺萬億條生命
to vaporize quadrillions of lives.
就從沒想過這有點
Never thought that was a little,
太心狠手辣了嗎
you know, much?
我早已下令銷毀它
I ordered it destroyed.
但有人把它藏起來了
And someone hid it.
你自己的人背叛了你
Your own people betrayed you.
反正 你們的企業文化都爛到到不可救藥了
Well, your corporate culture was straight-up shit.
而且你還是沒回答我的問題
And you didn't answer my question.
漸進線圈不見了
The asymptote coil is gone.
肯定是有人為了鋱元素把它拆走了
Someone must have scavenged it for the terbium.
那再找一個 這個東西應該能飛
Well, find another one, this thing should fly.
也許貨艙就有
Maybe the cargo hull.
別去
Huh. Oh, no, no.
每個人都待在一起 好嗎
Everyone stays together, all right?
降低你殺死我們的可能性
Limits the possibilities of you killing us.
我們去貨艙吧
Let's go to the cargo hold, please.
你不來嗎
Aren't you coming?
當然 我可太高興了
Yes. I couldn't be more excited.
當然 我可以下去幫你
Yeah, I could help you down there, of course,
但考慮到 控制我們的行動
but considering how, you know, control
是你整個身份的核心
is central to your entire identity
而我本來就不太能接受這種事
and the fact that I'm just not good at it,
所以我就站在這裡
I'm just gonna stand here
- 為了我們的關係 什麼也不做了 - 那你還真熱心呢
- and honor our relationship by doing absolutely nothing. - Helpful.
這叫做徹底的自我接納
It's called radical self-acceptance.
- 那你真是進步了 - 謝謝誇獎
- Evolved of you. - Well, thank you.
所以說 你能修好它嗎？
So, can you fix it?
我甚至不確定它是否壞了
I'm not even sure it's broken.
它只是缺了個零件
It's just missing a part.
看這裡 這些被亂扯的線路看著很嚴重
Look, this-this torn wiring looks dramatic,
但這設備本身就有冗餘設計
but this equipment has redundancy built in.
有一個簡單的解決辦法
There's an easy work-around.
唯一問題是 有人取出了θ節點
Except somebody ripped out the theta junction.
除此之外 這個東西應該可以用
Other than that, this thing should work.
好吧 也許我們的內鬼拿走了它
Okay, well, maybe our mole has it.
加勒特?
Garrett?
咋了
Yeah.
澤弗
Zeph.
澤弗去哪了
Where is Zeph?
澤弗 收到請回復
Zeph, come in.
澤弗 你能聽到嗎
Zeph, do you copy?
澤弗
Zeph.
加勒特 是你做的嗎
Garrett, was that you?
加勒特 剛剛那是什麼情況
Garrett, what the hell was that?
有人剛激活了天線陣列
Someone just activated the antenna array.
該死
Damn it.
具體情況如何
What's happening?
加勒特 情況簡報
Garrett, sitrep.
越來越棒了
This is going to be good.
上尉 收到請回復 完畢
Lieutenant, do you copy? Over.
安全
Clear.
這裡什麼都沒有
Nothing here.
怎麼會有人用這個來發出信號呢
How could someone have used this to send out a signal?
不可能 它少了一個部件
Impossible. It's missing a part.
有人把它打成了篩子
And someone shot it to hell.
我聽到有人在跑
I heard someone running.
澤弗一定是把θ節點放回去了
Zeph must have put the theta junction back in.
使用完畢後 射擊毀掉了陣列
Then shot it after he used the array.
所以他肯定是在擅離職守後繞回來的
So he must have circled back after he went AWOL.
澤弗來這個星球來阻礙我們
Zeph came down to this planet to sabotage us.
現在我們被困住了
And now that we're stranded,
他用陣列給同謀發了信息
he sent a message to whoever he's working with.
他會潛伏直到撤離的船抵達
And he'll lay low until his ride gets here,
然後溜之大吉
and then he's long gone.
那我們得先找到他
Then we need to find him first.
觀察者 能收到嗎
Observer, do you copy?
拜託 突襲者一號 我什麼時候收不到了
Please, Raider One, when do I not copy?
真好笑 情況如何
That's funny. Status?
我檢測到了不少干擾
I'm picking up a lot of interference,
但三錄儀顯示 澤弗的生命信號
but the tricorder shows Zeph's biosignature
就在這個區域 完畢
was just in this sector. Over.
收到 保持低調 保持隊形
Copy. Stay low and tight, people.
你曾效力的那個軍閥 吉裡
The warlord you served, Giri,
她後來怎樣了
what happened to her?
她死了 死於生前最愛的事
She died like she lived.
你知道我說的什麼
By that, you know what I mean.
她很幸運
She was lucky.
沒染上良心這種東西
She wasn't infected with a conscience.
染上?
Infected?
是啊
Yeah.
怪物就只能是個怪物
A monster can only be a monster.
一個會悔恨的怪物是沒用的
A monster with regrets is useless.
嗯 所以這就是你
Mm. So that's why you were hiding
躲在那個偏遠酒吧的原因
in a bar at the ass end of nowhere.
也許這就是你和31區的人合作的原因
Maybe it's why you're working with 31.
把自己的前科抹乾淨
To wipe your slate clean.
像我們這樣的人總是要付出代價的
There's always a price to pay for people like us.
如果你不同意 你就不會在這裡
You wouldn't be here if you didn't agree.
所以這就是你選擇我的原因
Oh, so that's why you chose me.
你認為我是一個有足夠感情的怪物
You think I'm a monster who feels enough
可以被控制
to be controlled
也還能做那些髒活
but still do the real dirty work.
不 我認為你想找回天賜之物
No, I think you want the Godsend back
因為你知道這是你救贖自己的唯一機會
because you know it's your one chance to redeem yourself
為你所做的一切贖罪
for all the shit you've done.
我想找回它 只因為它本就屬於我
I want the Godsend back because it's mine.
澤弗的外骨骼裝甲正在滲漏
Ah. Zeph's exoskeleton is leaking.
漏液更多了
Yep, more.
這邊
This way.
閃
Blip,
夾
Clip,
抓
Grip,
脊灰
Polio,
流感
Influensina,
牛痘
Cowpox...
你在念什麼呢
What are you saying?
我正在背誦我即將孵化的幼崽的名字
I'm reciting the names of me hatchlings.
既然你們中的一個要謀殺我
Since one of you is going to murder me,
我應該是見不到他們了
I'm never gonna meet them,
但至少我可以這樣紀念他們
but at least I can honor them
一個接一個
one by one.
旅行
Trip,
旅行二世
Trip 2,
扁桃體炎
Tonsilyitis,
克里米亞-剛果出血熱
Crimean-Congo Hemorrhagic Fever...
你要哭著念完19萬孩子的名字嗎
Are you gonna sob out 190,000 names?
你怎麼能這麼冷漠 如此無情
How can you be so cold and insensitive?
他有可能記錄下了發生的一切嗎
Might he have recorded what happened?
當然
Sure.
只是這段視頻很可能和他一起被謀殺了
Except the footage was probably murdered along with him.
我們可以將三錄儀連接到外骨骼裝甲上
We could connect one of the tricorders to his suit.
就算沒剩多少數據
Whatever data is left,
兇手也昭然若揭了
we'll know who did this.
說得好像我們都是嫌疑人一樣
You say that like we're all suspects.
並不是 好嗎
We're not. All right?
那時候我 法茲和喬久都在那艘船裡
Fuzz, me and her were in the scow when all this happened--
每個人都在彼此的視線範圍內
everyone in sight of everyone else.
沒一個人亂跑 沒錯吧
And nobody went anywhere, right?
對啊
Right.
這不是澤弗的
Oh, this is not Zeph's.
深褐色頭髮 25厘米
Brunette. 25 centimeters.
這太瘋狂了
This is insane.
別再坐立不安了
Stop fidgeting.
我已經和澤弗近距離接觸了一週了
I've been in close quarters with Zeph for a week.
行 所以你喜歡機甲什麼的
Okay, so you're into mecha boom-boom.
很多人類都是 不必害羞
Lots of humans are. No shame.
檢測到血液
呃 那不可能啊
Well, that's impossible.
加勒特上尉
Lieutenant Garrett,
痕跡匹配
為什麼你的指甲縫裡會有澤弗的血
why is Zeph's blood underneath your fingernails?
加勒特上尉
Lieutenant Garrett,
在澤弗的屍體上發現了你的證據
evidence from you was found on Zeph's body,
澤弗屍體上的證據也在你身上發現了
and evidence from Zeph's body was found on you.
不像星際艦隊的作風啊
Not very Starfleet.
我問心無愧
Oh, I am very Starfleet.
你清楚兇手並不是我
And you know I didn't do this.
你只是害怕任何有道德準則的人
You are just terrified of anyone with a moral compass.
但在那顆純潔的小心靈的深處
And deep down in that pure little heart,
你其實是個混亂小妖精 沒錯吧
you're actually a chaos goblin, aren't you?
- 我知道你是這樣的 小天使  - 別這麼叫我
- I know you have it in you, angel. - Don't call me that.
星際艦隊發現了這樣的你
Starfleet sniffed you out
把你放在了最能發揮你作用的地方
and put you in a place where you'd be most useful.
31區正是為那些打破規則
Section 31 is just the place for officers
卻又從未真正越界的軍官準備的地方
who bend the rules, never quite break them until they do.
而你 正好適合這裡
And you fit right in here.
你想怎麼折磨我都可以
You can torture me all you want.
但我堅持自己沒殺過人
You will never make me a murderer.
住手
No.
我們拿到錄像了
We've got footage!
住手
Stop!
快住手
這是我的裝甲
This is my suit.
我即是裝甲！
I am the suit!
裝甲就是我！
The suit is me!
等一下
One second.
我們是你的朋友
We were your friends.
曾是你的朋友
你殺不了我
You can't kill me.
澤弗 別
Zeph, no.
你不能
You can't kill...
澤弗是自殺的?
Zeph killed himself?
他為什麼要這麼做
Why would he do that?
抱歉讓您失望了 陛下
Sorry to disappoint you, Your Majesty.
這一切根本說不通
Look, none of this is making any sense.
是啊 非常之不合理
No, none of it makes a lick of sense.
他為什麼要這樣做呢
Why would he do this?
給我幾分鐘時間
Give me a couple minutes to...
我們沒時間了
We don't have minutes.
那就幾秒鐘行了沒
Well, then give me a couple seconds, then.
可能是你
Could be you.
原話奉還
但我連你長什麼樣都不知道
And I still don't even know what you look like.
你可以變成任何你想變的樣子
You could change into anything you want.
她是新來的 她才不在乎我們
She's new. She doesn't care about us.
我可是星際艦隊的軍官
I'm Starfleet.
當你在說我這套裝甲的時候
When you are talking about the suit,
就是在說我
you're talking about Zeph.
這可不是法茲
This isn't Fuzz.
這個瓦肯外表不過是台機器
The Vulcan's just a machine, you know.
我在裡面呢
I'm inside.
這是身材羞辱
Scale-shamer!
你絕對想不到我能進入多小的地方
You wouldn't believe the tiny spots I can get into.
比如 身體改造組件的內部空間
For example, the inner workings of body modifications.
當時他啟用了自動駕駛
There's an autopilot.
這是唯一合理的解釋
That's the only thing that makes sense.
你給瓦肯機器設定了自動駕駛程序
You set the Vulcan machine on autopilot.
所以當時它的反應才那麼古怪
That's why its responses were so strange.
你來不來
Aren't you coming?
當然
Yes.
你鑽進了澤弗的外骨骼裝甲
You flew into Zeph's exoskeleton.
你鑽進去之後
And once you were inside...
有人把西塔接口拆掉了
Somebody ripped out  the theta junction.
加勒特 澤弗去哪了
Garrett, where's Zeph?
然後你控制了澤弗的裝甲
Then you took control of Zeph's suit.
當別人在找他的時候
While the others were out looking for him,
你控制他溜回了通訊陣列
you made him sneak back into the antenna array
然後發送了那些信息
and send those messages.
不要這麼做
Don't do this to them!
我們是你的朋友啊
We were your friends.
然後你銷毀了所有證據
Then you destroyed the evidence.
還殺掉了澤弗
And you killed Zeph.
然後你再把這一切嫁禍給加勒特
And then you planted the evidence on Garrett here.
舉起手來 法茲
Hands up, Fuzz.
真是倒了血霉了
Oh, shite and ever shite.
阿洛克 你不會真的要信她的鬼話吧
You're honestly gonna believe what she says, Alok?
夸西 我們一起經歷了這麼多 你也信她的話嗎
Quasi, after everything we've been through?
我能先說一句嗎
C-Can I just say one thing first?
澤弗的外骨骼我還控制著呢
I'm still hacked into Zeph's exoskeleton.
喂
Come on!
說好的「不拋棄任何人」呢
What happened to "no crew member left behind"?
快一點啊
Come on, come on!
靠近他們
Get us closer.
接住你了
I got you. I got you.
還好有我
Nice and easy.
該死
Damn.
你很關注黑市的動向 沒錯吧
You keep tabs on the black market, hmm?
你就是在那聽說天賜之物的消息的
And that's where you heard about the Godsend.
你在乎這些幹什麼
Why do you care?
家人你都下得去手
You killed your family.
再多點人算什麼呢
What's a few billion more people, huh?
天賜之物在哪 你的同謀是誰
Where is it? And who are you working with?
你登上了皇位
You took your crown
他們卻痛苦地死在你的腳邊
while they died in agony not ten feet away.
你奴役了你唯一的朋友
You condemned your only friend to slavery,
居然還有臉在最後一刻給他一些憐憫?
and then you had the balls to offer him kindness at the end?
你怎麼會知道的
How could you know that?
你終於發現了
Glad you're catching on.
他把你耍了 女皇陛下
He played you, Emperor.
桑還活著
San's alive.
不可能
It's not possible.
絕對不可能 到底怎麼回事
That's not possible. How?
他訓練出了對毒藥的抗藥性
He built up an immunity from that poison, you know.
每次只多服用很小的劑量
Teeny tiny doses over time.
看樣子是小混蛋又贏了一次
Once again, small shite for the win, mama.
他在哪
Where is he?!
期待他的精彩表演吧
He's gonna put on quite the show.
你製造了天賜之物
You built the Godsend.
你製造了一個怪物
You made this monster.
全是因為你
This is all you.
小心點可以嗎
Be careful, all right?
我讓你小心點
I said be careful.
我還得用它活動呢
I have to get around in that.
你都能買得起一百多具身體了 還在乎這一具
You can afford a hundred of them now.
太好了
Oh, great.
這個能用不就行了
I'd settle for one that works.
所以就是這個
So that's it?
無敵的天賜之物
The almighty Godsend.
等你做上皇帝了
When you're emperor,
能不能給它換個沒那麼奇怪的名字
maybe start by naming it something less confusing.
離子風暴會聚倒計時
跨越兩個宇宙的通道打開時
Once that passageway opens up,
他會聯繫人族 他們會從中進入
he contacts the Terrans, they come through.
然後他們會在此引爆
They're detonating it here.
他就會成為帝國的新寵
And he'd be the darling of the Empire.
發生這樣的災難 星聯就會陷入混亂
So he throws the Federation into chaos...
星際艦隊自顧不暇
Starfleet will start scrambling.
入侵的完美時機
Perfect time to invade.
你創造了它
You gave birth to this thing.
我們要如何阻止
How do we stop it?
沒辦法
We don't.
我們被困在這 追不上他
We're trapped here, so we can't follow him.
通訊天線壞了 我們也無法警告任何人
The antenna's destroyed, so we can't warn anybody.
胡扯
That is bullshit.
你肯定有更好的辦法
You can do better than that.
我做不到
I can't.
天賜之物就像我自己
The Godsend is me.
我唯一無法戰勝的就是自己
I'm the only one I could never defeat.
過去總是纏著你不放
The past always catches up with you.
不是嗎
Right?
但並不意味著它總能贏
Doesn't mean it always wins.
每個安全屋都有備用計劃
Every safe house, I have a backup plan.
把那艘垃圾船修好
We'll get that scow running.
老大 那傢伙飛不起來的
Boss, the scow won't fly.
沒有漸進線圈就不可能
Not without an asymptote coil.
我們有一個
We have one.
我們必須追上桑
We'll catch up with San.
我們要阻止他聯繫人族帝國
We'll make sure he can't contact the Terrans.
你早把線圈拆出來了
You ripped out the coil.
有內奸在 我可沒法什麼都說出來
Couldn't tell you while a mole was still running around.
你個混蛋
Asshole.
小夸 去幫她一下
Okay, Quas, give her a rip.
還是只有一下反應
Still just one pulse.
來活了 朋友們
And we're in business.
我們只有不到三十分鐘時間
Okay, team, we have less than 30 minutes.
小夸 設定航線前往新月星雲
Quas, set a course for the Crescent Nebula.
路上將會非常顛簸
All right, this is gonna be bumpy and bad.
我推測桑的星艦會有武器
I'm assuming San's ship will be armed.
廢話 人族帝國能有不武裝的星艦嗎
Yeah, every Terran ship's armed.
對方有質子加農炮 魚雷
He'll have proton cannons, torpedoes,
而我們只有一堆垃圾
and we are a garbage barge.
有啥好笑的
Why are you laughing?
因為我想不出來還有什麼更糟的情況了
Because I can't imagine things getting much worse.
出發
Let's go.
所以 這艘船會在自身周圍製造牽引力場
So, this thing flies around in the middle of a tractor field.
人們向太空裡面扔垃圾
People jettison their garbage into space,
然後這種駁船會拖著垃圾和力場
and the scow flies around and drags the trash
一起飛行
along with the field.
牽引力場裡塞滿垃圾之後
Once the tractor field is full,
就會一起把垃圾甩進星雲裡
it dumps the trash in the Nebula
讓垃圾在輻射裡自行分解
where it disintegrates in the radiation.
我就是想確認一下
I just want to be clear.
你是說我們最有可能用的上的武器
You're saying that our best potential weapon is
是用來拖垃圾的牽引光束嗎
a beam for collecting garbage?
沒錯
Yes.
那太棒了
Great.
提醒下 你在那指手畫腳幫不上一點忙
Hey, being judgy never helped anything.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
輪機室
Engineering.
如果那是我們唯一的武器
If that's our only weapon,
我要把所有的能量都導入那裡
I'll redirect all power to the tractor beams.
這計劃確實不錯呢
That's actually a good plan.
（加密傳訊3）
（跨越宇宙的通道）
我們就位了
We're in position.
通道很快就會打開
The passageway will open soon.
你知道我在這一切結束後想幹什麼嗎
Do you know what I want when this is all over?
這麼大的一塊空域
Just a big space, you know,
我要和我的小傢伙們到處亂飛
for me hatchlings to tunnel and fly around and...
那你呢
What do you want?
我要菲莉帕喬久永遠沉淪於她的失敗之中
I want Philippa Georgiou to marinate in her own defeat.
我明白你們之間是那種
I get you guys are all
「永恆宿敵 性感的邪惡張力」之類的關係
"eternal nemesis, sexy evil tension" and stuff, but...
警報
Alert.
有飛船靠近
Incoming vessel.
檢測到碰撞航線
Collision trajectory detected.
她確實能把那玩意飛起來
Of course she got it off the ground.
我建議用魚雷解決他們
I say we should use the torpedoes.
對方發現我們了
They've picked us up.
光子魚雷來襲
Photon torpedo incoming.
擊中倒計時
Impact in five, four...
是時候進行規避機動了吧
Really want to take evasive action right now!
小夸 維持航線 護盾強度設置到最大
Quas, hold the course. Put everything in our shields.
她為什麼不改變航線呢
Why isn't she changing course?
我看起來像是算命師嗎
Do I look like a fortune teller?
我們有足夠的能量使用牽引光束鎖定他們嗎
Do we have enough juice to drag them with the tractor beam yet?
有 但我們沒法再承受魚雷的直接命中了
Yeah, but we can't take another direct hit.
魚雷即將命中 五 四 三
Incoming torpedo in five, four...
先維持航線 我們馬上就位了
Keep it steady. We're almost there...
閃避
Now.
警告 導航控制功能失效
Alert. Navigation control suspended.
他們在幹什麼 想拽死我們嗎
What are they gonna do, drag us to death?
她在阻止我和帝國取得聯繫
She's trying to stop me from reaching the Empire.
怎麼樣 大家沒事吧
How's everybody feeling about this?
這是唯一的辦法了
It's the only way.
這辦法有用
This can work.
輻射會削減他們的護盾
The radiation will wear down their shields.
是啊 但是輻射也會影響我們
Yeah, the thing is, the radiation hits us, too.
目標鎖定系統失效
Target lock malfunction.
魚雷無法鎖定目標 加農炮也離線了
I can't get torpedo lock. Cannons offline.
桑?
San?
桑
San.
桑!
San!
輻射已達致命水平
Radiation levels critical.
護盾失效 重複 護盾失效了
Shields are down. I repeat, shields are down!
他的呢
And San's?
還剩12% 仍在迅速下降
His are at 12% and falling fast.
等離子輻射來襲
Plasma incoming!
如果我們被捲入這樣的爆炸裡
We get caught with a burst like that,
我們就完了
and we're done.
這就是混亂 加勒特
This is chaos, Garrett.
你喜歡混亂沒錯吧
You know you love it, hmm?
直面它 接納它 享受混亂
Maybe let it in, make out with it a little.
這就是星際艦隊派你到此的原因
It's why Starfleet put you here.
混亂就像是我的炮友
Chaos is my friend with benefits.
就是這樣 越混亂越好
Yeah, Garrett, let's get messy.
怎麼樣
Hmm?
當然
Okay.
加油 小夸 你能行的
You got this, Quas.
沒問題
Uh-huh.
準備好了嗎
You ready?
桑的護盾只有4%了
San's shields are at four percent.
最後2%
Two now.
他的護盾已失效
His shields are down.
可以出發了
Good to go.
菲莉帕
Philippa!
我們這次
This contest only ends
不死不休
when one of us is dead!
引爆程序已啟動
Detonation sequence activating.
聽好了 我們納米人
See, the Nanokins,
不需要星際聯邦
we don't need the Federation.
向來如此
We never have.
早在你們這些龐然大物發現我們之前我們就在統治了
We ruled before you behemoths found us,
在你們死後 我們會再次統治
and we will rule again after you're gone.
猜猜誰會在待會的大爆炸中存活下來
Guess who survives very large explosions.
是我們納米人
Very small things.
好了 我先失陪了
Now, if you'll excuse me,
我得讓船脫離牽引光束
I need to cut our ship loose.
如果你的朋友在這個過程裡死了那真是抱歉
Sorry if your friends die in the process.
不 我在開玩笑
No, I'm joking.
我等不及要殺死他們了
I can't wait to kill them.
再見了 你個巨大狗屎
So long, you big lumps of shite!
誰在駕駛那艘飛船
Who's flying that?
根據傳感器 上面有一個微型生命
Uh, according to the sensors, one tiny life-form on board,
它在朝我們飛來
and it's heading right for us.
導彈鎖定
Plot missile lock.
我們只有垃圾 明白嗎 只有垃圾
We have trash, all right? Just trash.
但為一體
But one.
桑
San.
等待確認生物簽名
Awaiting biosignature confirmation.
我追蹤到法茲的穿梭艇了
I've got Fuzz's shuttle.
他要回到桑的船上
He's heading back to San's ship.
我們只能勉強跟上
We're barely keeping up.
跟住他
Stay on him.
提醒下 我們沒有任何武器
Uh, we don't have any weapons.
我們有一個滿載垃圾的貨艙
We have a payload bay full of trash.
不要跟丟那個穿梭艇
Do not lose that shuttle.
好吧
Okay.
我曾經什麼都不是
I was nothing!
那個男孩軟弱無力
That boy was soft, weak.
但在你腳下服侍的這些年教出了現在的我
But all those years under your heel taught me who I am now.
帝國艦隊將會穿過通道過來
The Empire's coming through that portal.
我的帝國
My Empire!
我們將統治這個宇宙
And we will reign over this universe
用公正又仁慈的手段 不像你
with righteous mercy, not like you!
從來不會有仁慈的獨裁者 桑
There are no benevolent dictators, San.
這是你教會我的
You taught me that.
我們還能回頭
We can come back from this.
我們可以重新開始
We can start over.
我愛混亂
Oh, I love chaos.
混亂是我的菜
Chaos is my jam.
我愛混亂
I love chaos.
加勒特 你在那裡邊幹啥呢
Garrett, what the hell are you doing down there?
夸西 我是個訓練有素的星際艦隊軍官
Quasi, I am a trained Starfleet officer
我也非常希望活得到能當上艦長的那一天
who fully intends on living long enough to be captain one day.
你得相信我 好嗎
You got to trust me, okay?
你好呀
Hi there.
真高興你找到了我
I'm so glad you found me.
你剛剛說啥了
What'd you just say?
是玩具說的
It's a toy.
看起來它來自一個德魯姆行星
Looks like it came from a Droom planet.
來一起找點樂子怎麼樣
Shall we do something fun together?
你還好嗎 星際艦隊女士
You okay down there, Starfleet?
哦 拜託 拜託 拜託 太好了
Oh, come on, come on, come on, come on. Yes.
我們不允許德魯姆科技進入聯邦
Oh, we do not let Droom tech into the Federation
因為他們用特瑞金作為電源
because they use Terrenium as a power source.
你是準備炸飛我們嗎
Oh, you're gonna blow us up, aren't you?
你最好希望這艘船的船體
You better hope that this ship's hull
用特莫礦加固過
is reinforced with Tomohite.
我是一名科學官
I am a science officer.
而科學就是受控的混亂
And science is just controlled chaos.
混亂 混亂 混亂
Whoa, chaos, chaos!
得了吧
Ah, come on.
起來 你個愚蠢的機器人
Get up, you stupid robot.
不 不
No. No.
不
No!
維持位置在法茲的飛船前
Stay in front of Fuzz's ship
這樣才能打開艙門往上倒垃圾
so we can open the payload bay.
呃 好
Uh, yeah.
我正想說呢
About that.
是這樣
Uh, thing is...
夸西 馬上就要發生非常大的爆炸
Quasi, there's about to be a very large explosion.
這個控制台的語言我看不懂
This console's in a language I don't know.
我能破譯其中一些
I can decipher some of it.
我只需要把它分解成語素
I just have to break it down to morphemes
然後 你知道
and, you know...
大爆炸要來了啊
Large explosion impending.
這兩個按鈕都有可能打開貨艙
Either of these two buttons could open the cargo bay.
好啊 那就都按了
Okay, so push them both.
這兩個按鈕也都有可能
Either of these two buttons could also
啟動自毀程序
initiate a self-destruct protocol.
反正怎樣都是爆炸唄
We're gonna blow up anyway.
嗯哼
Uh-huh
夸西 夸西 看著我
Quasi. Quasi, look at me.
你只需要做個決定
You just need to make a call.
你知道該做什麼
You know what to do.
好
Okay.
我們可以做永遠的好朋友
We can be friends forever...
你想聽點有趣的事嗎
Do you want to hear something funny?
我在自動駕駛狀態
I'm on autopilot.
什麼鬼
What the hell?
我們都要死了
We're all gonna die.
揮發性物質警告
不
No!
能和你在一起真是太好了
It's wonderful just to be with you.
好
Yes!
死吧
Die now.
去告訴你的家人你變成了什麼樣
Go tell your family how much you've changed.
桑
San.
不
No.
桑
San.
這不是我想要的結局
This is not what I want.
別死
Please.
我愛你
I love you.
我也愛你
桑
San.
對不起
I'm sorry.
真的對不起
I'm so sorry.
你 你是對的
You-you-you were right.
我仍然需要你
I still needed you.
我一直需要
I always needed...
讓我明白我是誰 即便是現在
To show me who I am, even now.
現在
Now.
我的皇帝
M-M... My emperor.
我的摯愛
My love.
不
No.
我們雙生一體
We are one.
直到永遠
Forever.
離子風暴即將會聚
Ion storm convergence imminent.
跨越通道正在打開
Passageway is opening.
生物簽名已確認
Biosignature confirmed.
六十秒後引爆
Detonation in 60 seconds.
計算機 目標鎖定跨越通道
Computer, target lock on the passageway.
目標鎖定已確認
Target lock confirmed.
如果你能回到過去
If you could go back,
回到跪在吉裡面前那時
and you were kneeling in front of Giri,
你會殺了她嗎
would you kill her?
你願意永遠結束所有的痛苦和硝煙
Would you put a stop to all the suffering and smoke forever,
就算這意味著你必須死去
even if it meant that you had to die?
我會的
Yes.
那麼我很高興認識了你 阿洛克·薩哈
Then I'm glad I knew you, Alok Sahar.
三十秒後引爆
Detonation in 30 seconds.
通道已打開
Passageway is open.
傳感器顯示他們啟動了脈衝引擎
Sensors show they've activated impulse engines.
什麼
What?
沒錯
Yeah.
你得把他們傳送回來
You need to transport them back.
-好的  -快點
- Yeah. Okay. - Now.
好的 好的
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
離子風暴在干擾我們
The storm's interfering.
我無法鎖定他們
I can't lock on to them.
十秒後引爆
Detonation in ten seconds.
快點 快點
Come on. Come on!
他們要沒時間了
They're running out of time.
我在努力
I'm trying.
五秒後引爆
Detonation in five,
四
four,
三
three,
二
two,
一
one.
加勒特上尉
Lieutenant Garrett?
瑞秋?
Rachel?
你還好嗎
You all right?
-我還好  -緩過來了嗎
- I'm okay. - Hmm? You here?
看來沒事
All right.
嗯 你還活著
Yeah. You're alive.
是啊 夸西把我們救出來了
Yeah, Quasi got us out.
-好了 好了 起來吧  -謝謝
- There we go. There we are. - Thank you.
你做到了
Oh, you did it.
我們贏了
Oh, we won.
成熟一點
Oh. Grow up.
這麼活潑讓我有點噁心
Perkiness is disgusting.
好吧
Yeah.
我知道了
I hear you.
就這樣了
It's happening.
通道在坍塌
The passageway's collapsing.
（最終傳訊 三個地球周之後）
原來你在這
There she is.
你的匯報如何
How was your debrief?
夠好的了
Oh, could've been worse.
他們給我發了邀請
They made me an offer.
然後呢
And?
我還在考慮
I'm sitting on it.
你呢
You?
還行 嗯
Meh. Hmm.
你覺得你能用這招
And how long did you think
騙過我幾次 嗯
you could fool me with this, hmm?
哪裡暴露了
What gave it away?
我看著你時你還會緊張
You still get nervous when I look at you.
你好啊 隊長
Oh. Hey, C-Cap.
放過那個可憐的傢伙吧
Leave that poor man alone.
維吉爾
Virgil.
給我的朋友上輪好酒
A round of elixirs for my friends.
沒問題 杜·弗朗克女士
Pleasure, Madame du Franc.
加勒特上尉
Lieutenant Garrett.
他們放你下船了
They let you off the ship.
實際上 現在是加勒特少校了
It's actually Lieutenant Commander Garrett now.
謝謝你們
Thank you very much.
如果這個小隊要成為常駐的
And if this unit is gonna be a permanent detail,
那你們絕對需要有人監督
then you all definitely need oversight.
我隨時都可能殺掉你們所有人
I may slaughter you all at any moment.
算是個雷點嗎
Is that a deal-breaker?
-不算吧 -無所謂啊
- Nah. - Whatevs.
反正你也不需要什麼理由
It's not like you need a reason anyway.
還真是 你就是個壞女人
It's true. You're a bad bitch.
帶著死亡凝視
With the stare of death.
哦 我們懂
Oh, we get it.
你是個可怕的冷血殺手
You're a terrifying, soulless murderer
我們永遠也不能真心相信你
who we can never truly trust.
我真為咱們感到高興啊
I love that for us.
總有人得活躍氣氛
Somebody's got to keep things lively.
說得好
Touché.
是啊 說得好
Yes, touché.
你說得對
You make a point.
敬我們
To us.
裡面沒放毒吧
This isn't poison, is it?
現在你把我們都叫過來了
And now that you have us all here,
下一步是什麼
what next?
也不全在
Well, not quite all.
女士們先生們 看舞台左側
Ladies and gent, stage left.
你一定在開玩笑吧
You got to be kidding me.
哦 我不是法茲
Oh, I'm not Fuzz.
31區從黑市上
Section 31 bought
買了兩個這種運輸工具
two of these conveyances on the black market.
我叫薇絲 是他的妻子
Name's Wisp. I'm his wife.
我來是為了抓到那個
And I'm here for when we catch up with
滿嘴扯謊 兩面三刀的混蛋
that lying, double-dealing son of a bitch.
呃 我們可是把他的船炸了的 女士
Uh, well, we blew up his ship, ma'am.
呃 法茲夫人
Uh, Mrs. Fuzz.
哦 親愛的
Oh, honey.
小東西有時能從大爆炸中生還
Little things sometimes survive big explosions.
等我們找到他 我要問他點事
And when we find him, I have questions.
好了 剛剛我們聊到哪了
Now, what are we talking about?
既然你問了
I'm glad you asked.
我正要讓小隊知道
I was just letting the team know.
管控給我們發了活
Control has a job for us.
我的理智已經向我
My better judgment has been
尖叫整整兩天了
screaming at me for two days now.
它一直告訴我 你們會害我丟掉工作
It keeps saying that you lot are gonna cost me my job.
說不定呢
We might.
那得是她
She might.
我告訴我的理智閉嘴
I told my judgment to shut up
去睡一覺
and take a nap.
因為我們還有工作要做
'Cause we have work to do.
有人去過圖爾卡納IV星*嗎
Has anybody been to Turkana IV?
（* 未來《下一代》4x06的故事正發生在此）
等下 你說的是圖爾卡納還是朱爾娜娜
Wait. Did you say Turkana or say Jur-Jurnana?
他以為是「你媽四星」
He thought "Your Mama IV."
你媽四星
Oh, Your Mama IV.
星際迷航中國字幕組譯製
翻譯: 瓦肯蔬菜湯
翻譯: 北窗高臥久息塵
翻譯: Soulzt
翻譯: 舟行萬里1234
翻譯: 是大e呀
翻譯: 諾北
校對: narwhrl
時間軸: narwhrl